<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Matthias Grenié – Computational Ecologist</title>
    <link>https://rekyt.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Matthias Grenié – Computational Ecologist</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>CC-BY 3.0, 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 18:38:36 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rekyt.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional Diversity</title>
      <link>https://rekyt.github.io/project/functional-diversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 18:38:36 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rekyt.github.io/project/functional-diversity/</guid>
      <description>Functional diversity (also trait diversity) is the diversity of functional characteristic of species.
The functional framework is useful to go beyond species identities.
Specifically it is useful to identify specific community assembly mechanisms.
However, it suffers for its biggest challenge of selecting functional traits and seeing which ones are available.
Throughout my research project I&amp;rsquo;ve mobilized the functional approach to develop new diversity indices, to understand the relationship between environment and birds&amp;rsquo; diets at global scale, to identify community assembly processes in specific communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macroecology</title>
      <link>https://rekyt.github.io/project/macroecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 18:02:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rekyt.github.io/project/macroecology/</guid>
      <description>Macroecology is the ecology of large spatial and/or temporal scale. The study at large ecological scales is a quest for the generality of ecological understanding (McGill 2019). I strongly think that studying broad scale phenomena help transcend the observed variability and contingency at local scale.
What methodological interest of macroecology is that it sollicits big datasets, which represent unique challenges both conceptually and technically. These big datasets help answer new questions irreducible to individual studies at local scale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools for Biodiversity Science</title>
      <link>https://rekyt.github.io/project/tools-for-biodiversity-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 18:02:36 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rekyt.github.io/project/tools-for-biodiversity-science/</guid>
      <description>I strongly think that biodiversity science needs robust standardized tools to make it a better science. This passes through formalizing the workflows and developping useful abstracted tools that can be reused across contexts.
One particular concern I have is that tool developers generally receive less credit than users while they support essential function for science.
Robust tools are crucial to develop a truly reproducible science.
This collective endeavor can only take place in a open-source software environment as scientific tools are part of the common goods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional Rarity: an additional biodiversity facet</title>
      <link>https://rekyt.github.io/project/functional-rarity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 17:30:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rekyt.github.io/project/functional-rarity/</guid>
      <description>Functional rarity also called functional originality or trait originality is the characteristic of species (or any other biological unit) that makes it different relative to a well defined set.
Why are original species interesting? Original species can provide: irreplaceable trait, meaning that original species disappear no other species are going to present the same trait values in the set; original specis may also represent original ecological strategies, if the trait space represents the niche space well then original species show original strategies; finally original species can help uncover specific community assembly processes, or combination of processes because they are not well predicted nor accounted for by current theories.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>